

RAFAEL MENDES

- DFTAILS -

Open to Relocate
Worthing
07477636606
mrrafaelmendes@gmail.com

- LINKS -

Linked In

□ SKILLS □

React is

Next js

JavaScript

Tailwind Css

Bootstrap

Stripe JS

React Hooks

Redux

UI/UX

Framer / Adobe xd / Figma

HTML - CSS

LANGUAGES

English

Portuguese

HOBBIES

Reading • Snowboarding • Start-ups

PROFILE

<u>rafaelmendes.co.uk</u> • 4 Years in Software • 8 Years in Leadership

Experienced with Sofware Engineering, UI/UX and Product Management.

Have experienced all three sections of the industry professionally and fell in love with code. Currently looking for an opportunity to expand my knowledge and experience.

★ PROJECTS

Amazon Replicated

React.js - Next.js - Redux - NextAuth - Stripe.js - Firebase/Firestore

As a skill assessment project, I re-created the Amazon website, a user is able to log in with google, add items to the basket and pay for them. Once successfully paid they are shown on the orders page.

Preview - Git

Airbnb Replicated

React.js - Next.js - Sanity.io Database

As a skill assessment project, I re-created the AirBnB website including responsive design, search functionality, calendar day picker, map integration, server-side rendered pages and more.

Preview - Git

Selected Tipping

React.js - Tailwind - Stripe.js

Built end-user tipping app allowing customers to pay for a percentage based fee or a custom amount with stripe.

Image

www.luxheating.co.uk

React.js - Next.js - React-Hook-Forms

Company website with a custom quote requesting system built with react hook forms.

Preview - Git

Resorts Website

React.js - Next.js - i18n

Company website created with Internationalization built to detect browser language and adjust accordingly.

Website - Git

See Other Projects

<u>See other projects</u> I was involved with both managing the Product Team or building the UI/UX with Framer, Adobe xd or Figma.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Business & Product Manager at Selected Group, Brighton

May 2019 — Present

Selected is a software company, operating mostly within the hospitality industry with a wide portfolio of solutions available internationally.

- Was Hands-on with coding front-end to a few tools alongside an engineering team.
- Helped create the concepts by liaising with the CEO & potential customers.

- Lead a team of 15 engineers and revamped the processes by implementing weekly code sprints, agile methodologies and code reviews.
- Created a cross-platform connection that resulted in an increase in our B2B sales by 285%
- Created, employed and trained a team of UI/UX Designers to result in tangible improvements in sprint delivery speeds.
- Ran customer interviews and demos to pinpoint pain points and transformed them into software solutions.
- Transformed our decision-making process by implementing key metric tracking tools.

Product Portfolio Included 11 products.

Product Manager - S. Resorts at Selected Group, Brighton

August 2019 — Present

Revolutionising Residential Communities with an ecosystem of Apps & Services.

- Fixed 80+ issues in the back office front-end backlog.
- Took over the product that had been stagnant for months and renewed it by setting its north start, creating user personas and building a team from our pool of engineers.
- Created a suite of tools based on residents problems and revived the app.
- Improved user activity by 420% and increased weekly users sessions from 1 to 3.9.
- Lead a team of 6 Engineers and 1 UI/UX, helped fill gaps in both departments when needed.
- Implemented weekly sprints, agile and shape-up methodologies.
- Built extra tools within the ecosystem to increase revenue streams.

Media Project Manager at Selected Group, Brighton

February 2019 — July 2020

Media Production studio built parallel to other projects while at Selected to improve revenue streams.

- Created and coached a team of animators, video editors and camera operators.
- Built a sprint methodology to increase speed and quality of deliverables
- Built a whole new Revenue Stream for the company.

Business Development Manager at Diliviri.com, Brighton

July 2018 — November 2019

Fleet software and service built to provide control back to food & retail companies trapped by titan solutions such as Deliveroo and Uber.

- Employed, managed and lead a team of engineers, sales & fleet drivers.
- Signed up 25+ Businesses locally to launch our original projects.
- Redirected the company's focus from physical services to purely working on the Dispatching software.
- Improved Driver Drops per trip by 45% while also identifying and improving other key metrics.

Previous Positions Available on LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mrrafaelmendes/

EDUCATION

F European Level 5, Epral, Evora

January 2010 — January 2013

■ REFERENCES

Leon Jeffery from Selected

Rafael's entrepreneurialism is always prevalent and paramount with his approach to any task he sets his mind to. He often bamboozled me with some of the innovative and pioneering software developments he helped to create and made exceptional USP's with our portfolio of products. This in turn made our software ground breaking and cutting edge and always set us apart from our competition. · Available on LinkedIn

Steven Van Zyl from Selected

Rafael is extremely effective when it comes to putting a team together & completing impossible tasks. There's almost nothing he can't achieve. Working in a team with Rafael is immensely rewarding. His drive is infectious, & his knowledge on business management & marketing is to be highly regarded. I wouldn't hesitate to follow Rafael into battle. · Available on LinkedIn

Harminder Swaley from Diliviri

I rarely come across real talents who stand out like Rafael. I had the pleasure of working with Rafael at diliviri.com his ability to handle multiple projects was unlike any I've seen before and made a dramatic increase in the productivity level of our company as a team member or a leader, Rafael earns my highest recommendation. · Available on LinkedIn

6 Other Recommendations Available on Linked